Preliminary Inventory of the B. E. (B. Edwin) Hutchinson Papers 1914-1961
Hoover Institution Archives
- Detailed listings of speeches, tracts, and other materials:
  - "Joint Statement of the Officers of the Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company before the House Committee on Education and Labor," (on the menace of "communistic" union leadership), 24 February 1947; Fred G. Clark and Richard Stanton Rinanoczy, How to Be Popular Though Conservative (New York: Van Nostrand, 1948); Clark and Rinanoczy, How We Live (1944); Clark and Rinanoczy, Money (1947); Automobile Manufacturers Association, Automobile Facts and Figures, 1946, 1947; K.T. Keller, "The Automobile Industry in the Postwar World," remarks made at the Seventh Business Conference, Graduate School of Business Administration, Stanford University, 22 July 1948; National Economic Council, "A Book-Review and Two Letters,"; and Samuel Crowther, "What Happened at Bretton Woods," published by the National Economic Council, July 1944. (Box 34)
  - Chrysler Corporation, " `Beyond the Facts and the Records', War Labor Board Panel Admittedly Ignores the Evidence and Rewards Union Irresponsibility,"; Chrysler Corporation Brief Before the National Labor Relations Board, Case No. 7-R-2038 in the Matter of Chrysler Corporation and Foreman's Association of America, Chrysler Chapter No. 3, prepared by Nicholas Kelley and T.R. Iserman, 20 March 1946 "What is A Foreman's Job?" newspaper advertisement, undated; Pattern For Strikes: How the Movement to Unionize Foremen Fits Into the Background of Organization Strikes in the Automobile Industry, Remarks by Nicholas Kelley before the National War Labor Board on 11 and 18 July 1944 Chrysler Corporation, Peacetime Enterprise Put to War Work (no date); exchange of letters between Walter P. Reuther and Herman Weckler, 26 July and 1 August 1946 regarding production and strikes; William Arthur, "Michigan G. O. P. Chief Sees Lesson in Party's Comeback: Republicans Can't Win on `Me Too' Platform, New Chairman Asserts (reprinted from the Des Moines Sunday Register, 22 May 1949); John W. Scoville, Chrysler Corporation Chief Statistician, "Collective Bargaining," speech before the Kiwanis Club, Detroit, Michigan, 8 August 1944; Walter H. Judd, M.D., "At the Crossroads of Our Foreign Policy," address before the Economic Club of Detroit, 2 February 1948; Clinton Davidson, Jr., Your Cost of Postwar Tax Proposals (Searcy, Arkansas: Harding College, 1945); Henry Hazlitt, Economics in One Lesson (New York: Pocket Books, 1946); and "History, Nature, Purposes, and Responsibilities of the Economists' National Committee on Monetary Policy, 19 September 1946, published by the Committee, 1946., (156 pages); (81 pages) (Box 35)
  - General Motors Corporation, An Analysis of the Pay Sick Leave Plan For Hourly Rated Factory Workers (1944) and H.W. Prentis, Jr., "Government's Place in Post-War Labor-Management Relations,' address given at the National Industrial Conference Board, New York City, 20 January 1944. The following titles were published by the Foundation For Economic Education, Irvington-on-Hudson, New York: The Law (no date); De Jouvenel, No Vacancies (October 1948), an anti-rent control tract; On Behalf of Liberty (July 1947); Betty Knowles Hunt, Show Me Any County (1947); Milton Friedman and George J. Stigler, Roofs or Ceilings? The Current Housing Problem (1946); Ludwig Von Mises, Planned Chaos (1947); Paul L. Poirot, The Pension Idea; V. Orval Watts, So You Believe in Rent Control? (no date); and Henry Hazlitt, Will Dollars Save the World? (1947). (Box 36)
  - Drawing, "Effects of Tax Rate Reductions From 1922 to 1928,"; Facts and Figures on War Finance (New York: The Tax Foundation, 1942); Henry M. Wriston, "A Fire Bell in the Night," (teachers' strikes), speech delivered at the Economic Club of Detroit, 25 October 1948; Andrew Dickson White, Fiat Money Inflation in France (Irvington-on-Hudson, New York: Foundation For Economic Education, no date), reprint of an 1876 publication; Fred Rogers Fairchild, Profits and the Ability to Pay High Wages (Irvington-on-Hudson, New York: Foundation For Economic Education, 1946); and F.A. Harper, High Prices (Irvington-on-Hudson, New York: Foundation For Economic Education, 1948). (Box 37)